{
  "question": [
    {
      "question": "What is the capital city of Puntland State of Somalia?",
      "options": ["Mogadishu", "Kismayo", "Bosaso", "Garowe"],
      "correctAnswer": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "In which year was Puntland officially established as an autonomous state?",
      "options": ["1960", "1998", "2004", "2008"],
      "correctAnswer": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the Primary economic activity in Puntland ?",
      "options": ["Agriculture", "Fishing and Livestock", "Mining", "Tourism"],
      "correctAnswer": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a key port city in Puntland ?",
      "options": ["Kismayo", "Eyl", "Berbera", "Bosaso"],
      "correctAnswer": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the traditional form of governance in Puntland ?",
      "options": [
        "Monarchy",
        "Clan-based system",
        "Military dictatorship",
        "communism"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first President of Puntland ?",
      "options": [
        " Dr AbdiWali Ali Gass",
        "Aaden Cadde",
        "Abdirahman Farole",
        "Abdullahi Yusuf Ahmed"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which city is known as the commercial hub of Puntland?",
      "options": ["Bosaso", "Garowe", "Galkio", "Qardho"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which ocean borders Puntland to the east ?",
      "options": [
        "Atlantic Ocean",
        "Indian Ocean",
        "Pacific Ocean",
        "Arctic Ocean"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which ethnic group makes up the majority of the population in Puntland ?",
      "options": ["Hawiye", "Isaaq", "Daarood", "Rahan-weyn"],
      "correctAnswer": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the climate like in most parts of Puntland ?",
      "options": [
        " Tropical rainforest",

        "Mediterranean",
        "Temprate",
        " Desert and semi-arid"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a traditional dish commonly eaten in Puntland ?",
      "options": ["Mandazi", "Mandazi", "Pilau", "Canjeero"],
      "correctAnswer": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a significant challenge to Puntlandâ€™s economic growth ?",
      "options": [
        "Lack of natural resources",
        " High population density",
        "Climate change and droughts",
        "Overreliance on manufacturing"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a major sport played in Puntland ?",
      "options": ["Football", "Tennis", "Rugby", "Basketball"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of livestock is most commonly reared in Puntland ?",
      "options": ["Cattle", "Camel", "Goat and sheep", "Donkey"],
      "correctAnswer": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the currency used in Puntland?",
      "options": [
        "Somali Shilling",
        "Ethiopian birr",
        "Kenyan Shilling",
        "US dollar"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Puntland city is located near the Gulf of Aden ?",
      "options": ["Galkio", "Eyl", "Bosaso", "Carmo"],
      "correctAnswer": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the mountain range in Puntland ?",
      "options": [
        "Almiskaad",
        "Golis Mountains",
        "Atlas Mountains",
        "Galgala Mountains"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the legislative body in Puntland ?",
      "options": [
        "National Assembly",
        "Federal Council",
        "Puntland Parliament",
        "Regional Assembly"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": 2,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which neighboring region borders Puntland to the west ?",
      "options": ["Somaliland", "Ethiopia", "Djibouti", "Kenya"],
      "correctAnswer": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Puntland is located in which part of Somalia ?",
      "options": ["Western", "Southern", "Northern", "Central"],
      "correctAnswer": 2,
      "points": 10
    }
  ]
}
